<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Batteries Not Included</title>
    <link>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Batteries Not Included</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;professional-profile&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Professional Profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a data scientist because I believe the universe around us communicates with countless signals. Some we can reliably measure, others we are still unaware of. However, understanding how to effectively capture, process, interpret, and understand those signals is critical to our progress both individually and collectively. I believe that at its very core, the role of a data scientist is to &lt;em&gt;improve the human experience&lt;/em&gt; by increasing our understanding of one another and the universe. Because of this perspective, I’m passionate about data and the development and efficient use of tools for interpreting and making use of that data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;competencies&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;communication&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve proven myself as both a capable writer and an enthusiastic and engaging speaker. I’m confident explaining complicated concepts in clear and concise terms and I’m as comfortable in front of the board as I am in front of my family. I’m always striving to improve my communication toolbox, from dynamic and intuitive visualizations to more engaging speaking practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;creativity&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creativity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself to be a highly creative individual. I enjoy tackling problems by finding clean, efficient solutions that age well. I think quickly on my feet and I have confidence in the ideas I come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;machine-learning&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m comfortable with a large variety of algorithms and frameworks and have repeatably demonstrated the ability to quickly learn new techniques and technologies. I’m at home with the complete machine learning pipeline, from conceptualizing the problem to preparing and cleaning the data to developing initial models to evaluating model performance to moving the final models into stable production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;skills&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;r&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;R&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyverse.org/&#34;&gt;tidyverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;shiny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Rdatatable/data.table/wiki&#34;&gt;data.table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.h2o.ai/&#34;&gt;h2o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mlr-org.github.io/mlr-tutorial/release/html/index.html&#34;&gt;mlr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;python&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Python&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sql&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SQL&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;unix&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Unix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;spark&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Spark&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;experience&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-scientist-front-analytics-march-2017---present&#34;&gt;Data Scientist | Front Analytics | March 2017 - Present&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed end to end dynamic analytics reporting tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created robust data pipelines and improved data join logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented key findings to company officers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built dynamic data reports using R and Shiny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;business-analyst-vivint.smarthome-june-2016---march-2017&#34;&gt;Business Analyst | Vivint.SmartHome | June 2016 - March 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built end to end machine learning pipeline for predicting and understanding customer churn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed actionable programs built around segmented customer behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created comprehensive customer profiles to guide marketing decisions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced and supported key ML technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-science-intern-tute-genomics-april-2015---june-2016&#34;&gt;Data Science Intern | Tute Genomics | April 2015 - June 2016&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed in-house analytics platform for visualizing and analyzing customer use data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented custom algorithm for computing customer health score&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented Google Analytics from the ground up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;education&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ms-data-science-university-of-the-pacific-2016---2018&#34;&gt;MS, Data Science | &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pacific.edu/Academics/Schools-and-Colleges/School-of-Engineering-and-Computer-Science/Academics-/Graduate-Programs/MS-in-Data-Science.html&#34;&gt;University of the Pacific&lt;/a&gt; | 2016 - 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bs-statistics-brigham-young-university-2009---2016&#34;&gt;BS, Statistics | &lt;a href=&#34;http://statistics.byu.edu/&#34;&gt;Brigham Young University&lt;/a&gt; | 2009 - 2016&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of Data Science 2017</title>
      <link>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/post/2017/06/summer-of-data-science-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/post/2017/06/summer-of-data-science-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I first learned of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23SoDS17&amp;amp;src=tyah&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#SoDS17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; through &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dataandme&#34;&gt;Mara Averick&lt;/a&gt; and was further enlighted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BecomingDataSci&#34;&gt;Data Science Renee&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; tweet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s how to participate in the Summer of Data Science &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/SoDS17?src=hash&#34;&gt;#SoDS17&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Data Science Renee (@BecomingDataSci) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BecomingDataSci/status/869240476892835840&#34;&gt;May 29, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and accompanying &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.becomingadatascientist.com/2017/05/29/summer-of-data-science-2017/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. As described, the basic premis is simple: set a goal to learn something new in the broad data science domain and make an effort to share the journey with others. As far as specific rules, Renee provides the following 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a thing or a short list of things related to data science that you want to learn more about this summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a plan to learn it (like an online course, a practice project, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share that plan on social media, then post updates as you make progress, with the hashtag #SoDS17.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea of &lt;strong&gt;#SoDS17&lt;/strong&gt; is simple and the rules are straightforward. In my opinion, that&amp;rsquo;s what makes this idea so fantastic - it allows me to pick &lt;em&gt;a few&lt;/em&gt; things I really want to focus on. Then I commit to accountability by sharing my goals publicly. This seems like a much better approach than my Trello board filled with an overwhelming number of loosely defined data science goals for myself. So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give &lt;strong&gt;#SoDS17&lt;/strong&gt; a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-goals&#34;&gt;My goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish an online voice

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a blog on &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.rbind.io/about/&#34;&gt;rbind.io&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;regularly update it&lt;/em&gt; (regularly updating entails at least once a month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since this post is part of said blog, the first part of this goal has successfully been completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get better at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyverse.org/&#34;&gt;tidyverse&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While this seems like a rather broad goal (and it kind of is) I&amp;rsquo;ve done my best to narrow it down to a few actionable and reportable items:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;http://r4ds.had.co.nz&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and blog about what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with each chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch related tidyverse sessions from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/conference/&#34;&gt;rstudio::conf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build my own deep learning model in R using Keras

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been intrigued by deep learning for a while now. Every time I hear &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bentaylordata&#34;&gt;Ben Taylor&lt;/a&gt; speak it get&amp;rsquo;s me all excited and motivated to learn all over again. However, my prior justification for not diving in has been &amp;ldquo;But&amp;hellip; Python&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. With the relase of &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.github.io/keras/&#34;&gt;Keras for R&lt;/a&gt; I can no longer lean on that crutch so it&amp;rsquo;s time to take the dive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help me wrap my head around the concepts and theory behind deep learning, I&amp;rsquo;m going to read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deeplearningbook.org/&#34;&gt;Deep Learning Book&lt;/a&gt; and blog about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I feel ready to dive in, I&amp;rsquo;ll create my own network (Using R + Keras) and publish a blog post about it
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there they are - my 3 &lt;strong&gt;#SoDS17&lt;/strong&gt; goals. Now that they&amp;rsquo;ve been released into the wild, it&amp;rsquo;s time to be serious about them. Feel free to follow up on my progress through &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Blair09M&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://batteriesnotincluded.rbind.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on my blog. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what I can accomplish this summer and sharing the journey with any who are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;julia&#34;&gt;Julia&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;me&#34;&gt;Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist at &lt;a href=&#34;https://frontanalytics.com/&#34;&gt;Front Analytics&lt;/a&gt; and a graduate student at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pacific.edu/Academics/Schools-and-Colleges/School-of-Engineering-and-Computer-Science/Academics-/Graduate-Programs/MS-in-Data-Science.html&#34;&gt;University of the Pacific&lt;/a&gt;. I received my undergraduate degree in statistics from &lt;a href=&#34;http://statistics.byu.edu/&#34;&gt;Brigham Young Unversity&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoy all things data, particularly all things data that live in the R universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an avid sports fan and an unashamed bandwagon Warriors fan (although I feel some legitimate connection to the team now that I attend school in the Bay Area). I grew up in Alabama so I&amp;rsquo;m also a committed Crimson Tide fan. When I&amp;rsquo;m not spending time with my family or doing data things, I&amp;rsquo;m often at the stove or at the grill as I consider cooking one of my main hobbies. I love racquetball and look for any opportunity I can to get out and play. Also, funnel cakes and chips and salsa are my ultimate weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-family&#34;&gt;My family&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://batteriesnotincluded-dev.netlify.com/img/family.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Family Photo&#34; /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m married to my incredible wife Brittany and we have two beautiful daughters and a bunny rabbit named Rex. Brittany and I met while we were both undergraduate students at BYU. Her degree is in Early Childhood Education and she taught first grade for 3 years before transitioning to a full time stay at home mom. Our two daughters (Eleanor (Ellie) and Charlotte (Charlie)) consume a large part of our available time. They are the greatest kids in the world (I am a bit biased, but the data I have indicates I&amp;rsquo;m also correct). Together we enjoy reading (we&amp;rsquo;ve amassed quite the home library thanks to my wife&amp;rsquo;s career), watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.imdb.com/title/tt3470600/?ref_=m_ttfcd_tt&#34;&gt;Sing&lt;/a&gt; on repeat, visiting the large collection of local splash pads and water parks (in summer of course), and taking long evening walks. When we have time for just the two of us my wife and I enjoy trying new local restaurants and watching mostly anything produced by the Food Network (we&amp;rsquo;re kind of food people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-in-a-name&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be fair to provide an explanation for the name &lt;strong&gt;Batteries Not Included&lt;/strong&gt;. I wish there was a really clever story behind it. Someday maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll make one up. However, the real story is that while competing in a Kaggle competition I was forming a team with some friends and we felt the need to have some sort of clever team name. Since none of us could come up with something compelling, I turned to Google for help and found my way to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teamnames.net/fantasy/random-team-name-generator&#34;&gt;random team name generator&lt;/a&gt;. After a few iterations, the name &lt;strong&gt;Batteries Not Included&lt;/strong&gt; came up and it was adopted as our team name. At the conclusion of the competition, I liked the name so much I kept it and decided to make it the name of my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, the phrase also fits very well into the data science universe. There are so many resources and algorithms and ready made solutions out there today, with more and more being developed and created every second. However, any package, library, algorithm, or solution is only as good as the data scientist behind it. In that way, &lt;strong&gt;batteries not included&lt;/strong&gt; suggests that every problem / analysis needs a good creative mind behind it to provide the power - to know how to properly select and use the correct tools for the job. This whole idea reminds me of a time golfing with my dad. After a particularly awful shot he joked with me that if he could just afford the clubs Tiger Woods played with, he would be a PGA level player. Of course, new and better and more expensive clubs aren&amp;rsquo;t the solution to my dad&amp;rsquo;s struggling golf game. The solution is, quite simply, more practice. And that&amp;rsquo;s what I intend this blog to be - a place for me to practice and expand my data science tool set.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>